# Folayan Iluyemi Michael

# Software Developer | Ambassador at Interswitch Group

Nigeria | +2348103817187 | foyemc@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/folayan-yemi 🕠 github.com/Yemmyfolayan

# **Summary**

I am a fourth-year Computer Science undergraduate, a Software developer, and an aspiring UI/UX designer & Fullstack developer. I strongly believe in teamwork, open-source projects, and community building. I have over 4 years of experience in Advanced level Computer Science coursework, such as algorithms and data structures; experienced with web technologies. I am dynamic, responsible, invested, and curious to discover new technology. I am also one of the best students in my faculty.

# **Work Experience**

#### InterSwitch Group & QuickTeller Ambassador

2020 - Till Present

• Interswitch Limited (Interswitch or the Company) is an Africa-focused integrated digital payment, The Quickteller Platform owned by Interswitch is's the leading multi-channel digital commerce and payment platform in Nigeria.

As a Quickteller Student Ambassador, I was tasked with the responsibilities of onboarding new users to the Quickteller platforms, and continue to nurture these new users to ensure they transact on a regular basis for their everyday payments. I'm also an advocate of the brand in building positive sentiment within your network both physically and digitally.

#### Comserve Technology INC, Canada, USA

2020 - Jan 2021

 Comserves Technology INC provides creative engineering and management solutions to clients and partners in several sectors on mission-critical projects.
Powered by innovative world-class talents, cutting edge technologies, and visionary leadership to deliver dependable and sustainable solutions. We provide creative engineering and management solutions to clients and partners in several sectors on mission-critical projects. Powered by innovative world-class talents, cutting edge technologies, and visionary leadership to deliver dependable and sustainable solutions.

#### NaijaHacks'19 Hackathon participant

12th, Dec, 2019-22th, Dec, 2019

• Team Hydra NaijaHack | Zone-Tech park Gbagada, Lagos, Nigeria.

Held a volunteer position as a software engineer for NaijaHack 2019 at Zone-Tech park, Lagos, Handled programming duties including web design and record keeping. Developed a WordPress site and blog with 20+pages. Customized a web app proposed to track all 958 delivery clients. Managed online ads to announce regular events. Worked with 4 team members to produce creative & efficient solutions.

#### Andela Learning Community (ALC 4.0)

2019

o Andela

Grow with Google has sponsored 30,000 developers in Africa to receive education from Pluralsight, supported by the Andela Learning Community. This partnership is a very special opportunity for developers aspiring to pass the ACE, MWS, or AAD exam. Participants receive free, limited-time access to Pluralsight Skills, with

### Skills

proficiency in JavaScript

React.JS library, React Native .RESTful APIs

Web Application Development

React.js, Redux, ApolloGraphQl, Javascript, Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices, (CI & CD), Google Cloud, JQuery,Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, NodeJS

Mobile Application Development

**NativeScript, React Native** 

Front-end development tools

Babel, Webpack, NPM

code versioning tools

Git, SVN

UI/UX Designs

FIGMA, WIX.

Project Management

Gant Chart, pert chart, version control System(Git, GitLab, GitHub), Microsoft Project.

Algorithm & Computation

C# and python

Operating system

handpicked courses focused on one of three areas: Mobile Web Specialist, Android Development, and Google Cloud.

#### Google Hash Code' 18 participant

20th, June 2018

• A Google organized annual coding competition based on the concept of Data Structure and Algorithm to solving real-life problems.

#### NaijaHacks'18 Hackathon participant

18th, Oct, 2018-22th, Oct 2018

• NaijaHacks

Nigeria's Official Hackathon that inspire a generation of Nigeria innovators to use technology to create solutions for their communities & Startups.

#### **Data Science & Artificial Intelligence participant** 15th, May, 2019-21th, May 2019

• at COVEN LABS (May Cohort)

Recommended by the University as a beneficiary of the May Cohort 2019 Scholarship, Data Science & Al Bootcamp at COVEN LABS, Akure, Ondo State

#### Google Digital Skills for Africa participant

16th, Aug 2019

o Google

Digital Skills For Africa is a Google initiative in conjunction with various training partners, which aims to train young people in digital skills. The future of work is in the online world.

#### **Community Member**

2017

- Developer's Student Club (DSC) FUTA
  - Student developer & Facilitator (Web App development).
- Google Developer's Group (GDG FUTA).
  - o Member.
- Association of Computing Machinery(ACM).
  - o Member.

## Certification





**JavaScript Certificate** 

**Google Digital Skills** 

# **Education**

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) in Computer Science 2016 - 2021 Federal University Of Technology Akure.

A Fourth-year student who has acquired more knowledge in:

- JavaScript.
- Frameworks (React JS, Gatsby JS, GraphQL).
- Web Technologies.
- Algorithm and Data structure.
- Digital Designs (UI/UX).
- Object-Oriented Programming.
- Digital forensics.
- Computer Troubleshooting.

#### **Debian Linux, Windows OS**

Operating System

Windows and Linux-Ubuntu

Business & Leadership

**Teamwork & Organization** 

**Productivity & Passion At work** 

Dev post article writing

Medium, Dev Post, Twitter, Hash Node

# Objective

An Internship that allows me to practice and implement Computer Science theories and software development for knowledge, experience and to validate my B.Tech degree.

#### **INTERESTS**

- Coding
- Innovation
- Optimal solution
- Music
- Games
- Football

- Linux & Windows Operating System.
- System Analysis & Designs.

# **Projects**

Intrio Basket

march 2020 - present

open source apps built with React.JS library (collaborative project)

https://intriobasket.ng

CamShopify

Comserve Geo Tagging App

https://camshopifycomserve.netlify.app/

Tugapimage

2020 - present

tugapimage.com is a Brand Photography WordPress website <a href="https://tugapimage.com">https://tugapimage.com</a>

Exceptos Swag store is a basic e-commerce PWA, June 2019 - present https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/exceptos-store https://store.exceptos.com

Sound-mansion

2020 - present

SoundMansion is modeled as a community-driven music streaming service where you can experience every kind of music which a commercial music streaming service like Spotify, Soundcloud, and others fails to deliver.

- https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/OrilsClosetEcommerce.git deployed on Netlify.
  - https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/soundman.git, deployed on Netlify
  - https://soundmansion.netlify.com

# E-commerce Shopping Cart

2019 - present

an online retailer's site that facilitates the purchase of wears, accessories & wristwatch. It accepts the customer's payment and organizes the distribution of that information to the merchant, payment processor (PayPal).

• https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/OrilsClosetEcommerce.git deployed on Netlify.

Edu-Test

2018 - present

A site for undergraduate Quiz platform developed on API CBT.net, Similar to the Federal University Of Technology Akure, Computer Based Test platform to assist students in preparation for the main Test and Examination.

• https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/E\_Testing.git

Portfolio website

2019 - present

- https://michaelfolayan.netlify.com
- source code: https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/Personal-Website.git

JavaScript learning path for newbies

2020 - present

contributed to the open source project by Asabeneh

• https://github.com/YemmyFolayan/30DaysOfJavaScript.git



Created with 📅 VisualCV